[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c012", "question": "What did a Cordwainer make?", "answer": "Shoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd9936ce05a3942286d79", "question": "What was Red good at doing in prison in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Smuggling contraband into the prison.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dcd", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"smorgasbord\"?", "answer": "Swedish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef624c6ce05a3942286e5d", "question": "Who was the original voice of Charlie in TV\u2019s \"Charlie\u2019s Angels\"?", "answer": "John Forsythe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab192bbaab681b09292190", "question": "What is Donald Duck\u2019s car?", "answer": "A 1934 Belchfire Runabout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a39c", "question": "What is the fifth largest country in the world?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0fa", "question": "What infamous assassin hollered \"Sic Semper Tyrannis\" as he made his escape?", "answer": "John Wilkes Booth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b957", "question": "What golfer is nicknamed the \"Golden Bear\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicklaus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66c", "question": "In 1976, Viking 1 made history after it landed where?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339102", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "Georges Bizet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5ed26ce05a3942286e3a", "question": "What baseball legend has a cameo in \"The Benchwarmers\"?", "answer": "Reggie Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e3", "question": "What is kept in a ship's binnacle?", "answer": "Compass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa9", "question": "What is Diazepam better known as?", "answer": "Valium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c943", "question": "What type of creature was an Archelon?", "answer": "A Turtle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02f", "question": "What type of food is Fontina?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338909", "question": "Who wrote \"The Hunchback of Notre Dame\"?", "answer": "Victor Hugo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc68", "question": "What college did Brett Favre attend and play football for?", "answer": "Southern Mississippi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a610", "question": "What is the world\u2019s most southerly capital city?", "answer": "Wellington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d56", "question": "What is author J. K. Rowling's full birth name?", "answer": "Joanne Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339457", "question": "How many cars does Memphis have to steal to save his brother in \"Gone In 60 Seconds\"?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95d", "question": "What is the first prime number that comes after 100?", "answer": "101", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be46", "question": "The VIC-20 and PET were personal computers manufactured by which company?", "answer": "Commodore International, Ltd.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ac", "question": "What New York City landmark is nicknamed \"The Crossroads of the World\"?", "answer": "Times Square", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b813", "question": "What is the Jewish New Year called?", "answer": "Rosh Hashanah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa4", "question": "What is philology the study of?", "answer": "Languages", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd3", "question": "What century did Rembrandt live in?", "answer": "17th", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339542", "question": "What kind of dog is Ren on \"The Ren and Stimpy Show\"?", "answer": "Chihuahua", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3b", "question": "What Reds and Tigers manager was nicknamed \"Captain Hook\" for his tendency to pull pitchers early?", "answer": "Sparky Anderson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c48", "question": "Who is the main character in Ayn Rynd's \"The Fountainhead\"?", "answer": "Howard Roark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bf", "question": "Yellowstone Lake is located in which US state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173c3444491cbd7c5a17a4", "question": "What collectively-named languages evolved from Vulgar Latin?", "answer": "Romance or romanic language -- The five most spoken romance languages are Spanish, French, Portuguese, Italian and Romanian.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d7fa2596a59cbdfbd3bd", "question": "The Colossus of Rhodes was dedicated to which god?", "answer": "Helios", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c8f30775fa611bce67e6", "question": "\"A capella\" is an Italian term that means what?", "answer": "\"In the manner of the chapel\" --  A capella music is a group or solo performance without instrumental accompaniment.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a552373e1c6f9840ba3193", "question": "What color flag indicates a fair throw in the shot put?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81ba9d0de9af39e9d467b", "question": "Who was the first president to be born a U.S. citizen?", "answer": "Martin Van Buren", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899dd160d398dc9cf7a6af", "question": "Who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973?", "answer": "Henry Kissinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339181", "question": "Who was the female lead character in the movie \"Three Colors: White\"?", "answer": "Julie Delpy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017375e44491cbd7c5a1789", "question": "Who designed and built the interior structure of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "The innovative designer and builder Gustave Eiffel and his structural engineer, Maurice Koechlin designed and built the statue.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e1478f9dd42e4a67cb8d3ec", "question": "What automobile brand invented the three point seatbelt, then waived their patent rights, allowing competitors to copy?", "answer": "Volvo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c524", "question": "Where in your body would you find your hippocampus?", "answer": "Brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5fba6ce05a3942286e46", "question": "What famous musician was nicknamed Mr. Showmanship?", "answer": "Liberace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c4", "question": "Tin cans were invented in 1810, but is it true that can openers did not appear until 50 years later?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a49220565ad31a57c7bf", "question": "Which President kept a 1,000+ lb. block of cheese in the White House?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b37", "question": "Which of the Seven Dwarfs comes first alphabetically?", "answer": "Bashful", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51f", "question": "What are the four largest islands of Japan?", "answer": "Honshu, Kyushu, Shikoku, Hokkaido", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b46", "question": "What animated TV character had a saxophone mentor named \"Bleeding Gums\" Murphy?", "answer": "Lisa Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a3", "question": "What Spanish explorer is credited with discovering the Mississippi River?", "answer": "Hernando De Soto", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cc45bb53d1af658864df", "question": "How many years after the founding of the company did Hallmark release its first Christmas cards?", "answer": "5 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e3f7525cb9e8bda682136f", "question": "The wreckage of which ship was discovered in 1985?", "answer": "Titanic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb5", "question": "What was the first Pokemon to be trademarked?", "answer": "Mew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab16", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 602?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd54", "question": "The Obie Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Off-Broadway theater", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c468", "question": "Who was the first person to attach an eraser to the end of a pencil?", "answer": "Hyman Lipman", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b6a8e662d71a5365100b", "question": "What author became famous for his six-volume biography of Lincoln?", "answer": "Carl Sandburg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eae", "question": "Who won Pulitzers for his plays \"A Delicate Balance\", \"Seascape\", and \"Three Tall Women\"?", "answer": "Edward Albee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90f", "question": "What major river runs through Amsterdam?", "answer": "Amstel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff213af31a458464a93c451", "question": "Pineapples, kiwis and papayas contain enzymes that can do what to meat?", "answer": "Tenderize it", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a98e361d1b4d384d5d693", "question": "Which major lake is near the Ponderosa Ranch in the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Lake Tahoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb0527e83c707845b2103", "question": "Which comic strip inspired the name of Stegosaurus tail spikes?", "answer": "\"The Far Side\"", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c2", "question": "What is the world's fastest growing plant?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339579", "question": "In A Christmas Carol what song is sung outside of Scrooge's office?", "answer": "God Rest Ye Merry Gentlemen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3d", "question": "What humorist often reminisces about his high school rock band, the Federal Duck?", "answer": "Dave Barry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e39", "question": "According to Fountains of Wayne, whose mom \"has got it goin' on\"?", "answer": "Stacy's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd9", "question": "What two-word Latin phrase means \"the reverse order\"?", "answer": "Vice versa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392eb", "question": "In the 1991 movie \"Thelma and Louise\" who plays the part of Thelma?", "answer": "Geena Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd72fe347d002c297e4bf", "question": "Which US state gets the most rainfall?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a76", "question": "What was the name of the lead character in the novel \"The Scarlet Letter\"?", "answer": "Hester Prynne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5c596ce05a3942286e1f", "question": "What did the Crocodile swallow in Peter Pan?", "answer": "An alarm clock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c538fbde8045e48466a9", "question": "What four-legged animal is considered a marine mammal?", "answer": "Polar bear -- They rely on the sea to provide their main food source (mostly seals) and need sea ice platforms to hunt them.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b091e662d71a53650fca", "question": "What part of New York did Vito Corleone grow up in?", "answer": "After Vito flees Sicily, he finds shelter with the Abbandando family in Little Italy, New York.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56f", "question": "Which US state has shoreline along the Gulf of Mexico and the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a381", "question": "Which continent are the Balkans a part of?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb00", "question": "Azote is an old name for what element?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc47f6ce05a3942286f33", "question": "Who directed the film \"The Silence of the Lambs\"?", "answer": "Johnathan Demme", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb72", "question": "What was pictured on the face of the US penny just prior to Abraham Lincoln?", "answer": "Indian head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29b", "question": "What bird did Ben Franklin suggest replace the bald eagle as a national emblem?", "answer": "The wild turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ff", "question": "What was the first man-made insecticide?", "answer": "DDT", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60078ae40eee65b76b9f2661", "question": "Following a steel shortage, what kind of ships were built during World War I?", "answer": "Concrete (24 ships were completed too late to join the war efforts, but the concept was applied to make ships used during World War II.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a1", "question": "Which band comprises sisters Andrea, Sharon, and Caroline with their brother Jim?", "answer": "The Corrs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3f", "question": "What is the first book of the Bible named for a woman?", "answer": "Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac4", "question": "What \"C\" word is the name for a two-hulled boat?", "answer": "Catamaran", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cae", "question": "Who wrote \"Tarzan of the Apes\" in 1912?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bb357612627b8fe95581be3", "question": "What is the capital of the Australian state, Queensland?", "answer": "Brisbane", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f6fb1a9e54d890926f6d2", "question": "Which country is home to the colorful Rainbow Mountain?", "answer": "Peru -- AKA Vinicunca, it achieves its vibrant hues thanks to natural weathering, which has exposed mineral strips in the earth.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338adb", "question": "The comic strip \"Spy vs Spy\" debuted in which year?", "answer": "1961", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397bc", "question": "Who became the first female head writer in the history of Saturday Night Live in 1999?", "answer": "Tina Fey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac89", "question": "How were Theodore and Franklin Roosevelt related?", "answer": "They were fifth cousins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338936", "question": "Whose best-selling diary was written by Helen Fielding?", "answer": "Bridget Jones's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8c56ec223966ae8f8848", "question": "The 1994 \"Leon\" was the motion-picture debut of which one of its stars?", "answer": "Natalie Portman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe378ce0ada16518afdc054", "question": "Which popular Christmas song was originally written for a Broadway musical?", "answer": "\"White Christmas\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad24", "question": "How did the ancient Irish mark their land?", "answer": "The rock they cleared was the land they had.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6d", "question": "What are the names of the four Musketeers?", "answer": "Athos, Aramis, Porthos and D\u2019artagnan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c96e", "question": "Ariel is a moon of which planet in the solar system?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c5", "question": "Eric Carmen's hit song \"Hungry Eyes\" has been used in a popular TV ad campaign for what snack food?", "answer": "M&Ms", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c36ad815febcc896f9269", "question": "Who runs the \"Leftorium\"?", "answer": "Ned Flanders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca10", "question": "Pediculophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Lice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e1", "question": "Calamarata pasta is shaped like what?", "answer": "Wide rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1e", "question": "What does \"dakota\" mean in the Sioux language?", "answer": "Friend", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be52", "question": "Perfecto, torpedo, and parejo are all shapes of what?", "answer": "Cigars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c4", "question": "Ladin is primarily spoken in which area of the world?", "answer": "Northern Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec849eec223966ae8f8800", "question": "Sozin's comet is an astrological event that occurs in which television series?", "answer": "\"Avatar: the Last Airbender\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8a", "question": "What did the 13th Constitutional Amendment ban?", "answer": "Slavery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c8", "question": "Who authored the song \"In the Ghetto\"?", "answer": "Mac Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc25", "question": "In what year was Wikipedia officially launched?", "answer": "2001", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a58c20565ad31a57c7ce", "question": "What dessert did Margaret Thatcher help develop?", "answer": "Soft-serve ice cream", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e93a6f9d6f11f394a3b2d56", "question": "What is the Star Wars character Emperor Palpatine's first name?", "answer": "Sheev", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aaf", "question": "Who wrote, Once Upon a Christmas in 1972?", "answer": "Pearl S. Buck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339372", "question": "In the movie \"Batman\", what does the Joker call his secret ingredient?", "answer": "Smylex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef95a46ce05a3942286e98", "question": "What is the name of the patient in the game Operation?", "answer": "Cavity Sam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a6", "question": "Apple's CEO Steve Jobs was known for wearing what color turtleneck?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6012188e63c99d48cd169af5", "question": "What do you call a group of unicorns?", "answer": "A blessing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede4ae6ce05a3942286de0", "question": "In which 2001 movie did Tim Roth play the character General Thade?", "answer": "\"Planet of the Apes\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c299", "question": "What is the hardest substance in the human body?", "answer": "Enamel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8d7712b42d4a3561a9f0d", "question": "What fast food businessman does Michael Keaton portray in the 2016 film \u201cThe Founder\u201d?", "answer": "Ray Kroc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a22", "question": "What movie features the following line \"This war talk\u2019s spoiling all the fun at every party this spring\"?", "answer": "Gone with the Wind", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59c1cdfe7bd84c0ea43ad432", "question": "Which city is directly northwest of Windsor, Ontario?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339efc", "question": "What TV show opened with a \"control voice\" saying, \"Do not attempt to adjust the picture\"?", "answer": "The Outer Limits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3f9dc73aa70ea0b70b01", "question": "What does the Japanese term \"Sandai Wagyu\" translate as?", "answer": "Three Big Beefs (Sandai Wagyu are \"the three big beefs\" - Matsusaka, \u014cmi and the most-famous of all, Kobe.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008d9ccf842fa4c4ba96ab", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Oedipus marry?", "answer": "Jocasta, his mother", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df5", "question": "What Broadway team collaborated on \"Flora the Red Menace\" before writing \"Cabaret\" and \"Chicago\"?", "answer": "John Kander and Fred Ebb", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ce", "question": "What is a woolly bear?", "answer": "Caterpillar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b322", "question": "What Asian leader was known as the \"little brown saint\"?", "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339280", "question": "What season 13 competitor in the TV show \"Big Brother\" told Rachel that she rooted for her in season 12?", "answer": "Cassi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a702", "question": "What is the official state animal of Kansas?", "answer": "The bison", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe526621bf59ab7d2e380f7", "question": "What is the coldest permanently inhabited town on Earth?", "answer": "Oymyakon, Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69bed20565ad31a57c765", "question": "Who was the first U.S. senator to be elected president?", "answer": "James Monroe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc1bc6ce05a3942286f14", "question": "Lee Marvin won an Oscar for his role in what movie?", "answer": "Cat Ballou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe903d901dd7bf43be5e871", "question": "Which U.S. federal agency provides protection for the federal judiciary?", "answer": "United States Marshals Service", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8feee01dd7bf43be5e85e", "question": "Whose image is on the U.S. half-dollar from 1916 to 1947?", "answer": "Lady Liberty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60023f054be4723ccac22161", "question": "As of 2020, what was the name and breed of the tallest dog ever?", "answer": "A Great Dane named Zeus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1aa", "question": "What was the former name of Times Square before being renamed in 1904?", "answer": "Longacre Square", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe771d1eec85e375820b300", "question": "Which country hosts the world's highest marathon?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339915", "question": "In the movie \"Austin Powers in Goldmember\", what country is Goldmember from?", "answer": "Holland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b497649076251badbeaae", "question": "Where in the world was Richard Nixon when he delivered his infamous \"I am not a crook\" speech?", "answer": "Disney World (Orlando, Florida)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8b", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"A Place in the Sun\" based on?", "answer": "An American Tragedy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2cff32596a59cbdfbd375", "question": "Who said, \"Nearly all men can stand adversity, but if you want to test a man's character, give him power\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339410", "question": "What was the maiden name of \"Leave It to Beaver\" TV mom June Cleaver?", "answer": "Bronson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feba93e7e83c707845b20d4", "question": "What is suspended from the ceiling of the American Natural History Museum?", "answer": "Blue whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "595641ae803c1f1ebcc4a02a", "question": "The ball on top of a flag pole is called a what?", "answer": "Truck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b8", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"I thought I'd get into shape, so i've been drinking nothing but milkshakes.\"?", "answer": "Krusty the Clown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e8d", "question": "Venetian painter Jacopo Robusti was better known by what name?", "answer": "Tintoretto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eeb", "question": "What movie's protagonist is named Lightning McQueen?", "answer": "Cars", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f1", "question": "Who played the lead female in the 1956 film \"Meet Me in Las Vegas\"?", "answer": "Cyd Charisse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ba", "question": "Which is the world's northernmost capital city?", "answer": "Reykjavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c738", "question": "Dry Ice is the solid form of what chemical compound?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f52", "question": "What song begins with the words \"Betty, is that Jimmy's ring you're wearing?\"?", "answer": "Leader of the Pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b78c", "question": "Grits are typically made from what grain?", "answer": "Corn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef61f16ce05a3942286e59", "question": "What does the \"MS\" reference in \"MSNBC\"?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b030", "question": "Before becoming Vice-\u00adPresident, Joe Biden represented what state in the US Senate?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f6f7fe83fe1f2a824c1f", "question": "After Jesus fasted in the desert, what was His first temptation in the wilderness?", "answer": "Turn stone into bread", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c523877e98cb977789ab", "question": "Which island was once named the \"Island of the Pelicans\"?", "answer": "Alcatraz Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fdb", "question": "The family on the TV show \"Married...with Children\" was named in honor of what wrestler?", "answer": "KIng Kong Bundy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8e", "question": "What color are the $1 bills in a standard game of Monopoly?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959d", "question": "What is Indiana Jones searching for in the movie \"Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade\"?", "answer": "The Holy Grail", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab952086faa38a764be512", "question": "What was the first production car to break the 200 mph top speed limit?", "answer": "The Ferrari F40", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cafc", "question": "Which drug can be extracted from the bark of the cinchona tree?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be13", "question": "What specific animal appeared above the \"Don't Tread on Me\" motto on early American flags?", "answer": "A rattlesnake", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029e85cad1ec93f27df756", "question": "What country does Cafe au lait originate from?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66464a5bfecdd737e0854", "question": "When did scientists start giving hurricanes human names?", "answer": "1953", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93e", "question": "What was the only nation to qualify for all 16 soccer World Cups in the 20th century?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935f", "question": "What was in the jaws of the swordfish mounted on the wall in the Addams Family house?", "answer": "A human leg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b77de662d71a53651012", "question": "What famous philosopher poet said, \"I awoke this morning with devout thanksgiving for my friends, the old and new\"?", "answer": "Ralph Waldo Emerson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c906", "question": "What color is the tip of a Canada lynx's tail?", "answer": "Black", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a551d83e1c6f9840ba3190", "question": "What is a \"Pickelhaube\"?", "answer": "A spiked German helmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cdd6bb53d1af658864ed", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "1939", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b63101dd7bf43be5e7d6", "question": "What is Cinnamon Toast Crunch cereal called in the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Curiously Cinnamon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65984ae7e414034b5af01", "question": "Which Founding Father had a house which was discovered to have had about 1200 bone pieces from about ten human skeletons?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c646", "question": "What is the name of Earth's first artificial satellite?", "answer": "Sputnik", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b36ebf1c3f17ccc40c8e0a", "question": "Which of Mark Wahlberg's brothers appears in the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "Donnie Wahlberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2fe", "question": "What Danish peninsula lent its name to the largest naval battle of World War I?", "answer": "Jutland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af87", "question": "What did the British army do to the US Capitol building in 1814?", "answer": "Set it on fire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e94d1835ea27d7a1303aed4", "question": "One legend says Clovis, king of the Franks, adopted what symbol after flowers revealed a safe river crossing for his army?", "answer": "Fleur-de-lis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59db78230ab2c8f322317ff2", "question": "Which author wrote about the Cornish seaside boarding school Malory Towers?", "answer": "Enid Blyton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6be", "question": "The Mississippi River flows into what body of water?", "answer": "Gulf of Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c990", "question": "Which Russian scientist used dogs to study conditioned reflexes?", "answer": "Ivan Pavlov", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c784", "question": "Aeolian processes pertain to the study of what weather activity?", "answer": "Winds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75e", "question": "What organ gave us the word \"hysterical\"?", "answer": "The uterus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133addb", "question": "Who was the first US president to have a woman serving in his cabinet?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef64996ce05a3942286e67", "question": "What is the smallest theater on Broadway?", "answer": "The Helen Hayes Theatre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b02", "question": "The ending vocal riff of what 1966 Frank Sinatra song inspired the name of cartoon character dog Scooby-Doo?", "answer": "Strangers in the Night", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d16", "question": "What gangster movie was originally titled \"The Menace\" and eventually subtitled \"The Shame of the Nation\"?", "answer": "Scarface", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c740", "question": "What is the most populous bird in the world?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba4", "question": "What was the title of Hootie & the Blowfish's 1995 debut album?", "answer": "Cracked Rearview", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e6", "question": "Which actor played the role of Trinity in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Carrie Anne-Moss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea45e4ff048f679a45ab9b", "question": "Dimples on golf balls help increase speed by reducing what?", "answer": "Drag", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe1332be39efa6330e0fedb", "question": "Which is the driest, non-polar desert on Earth?", "answer": "Atacama Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbf806ce05a3942286f00", "question": "In the television series \"Magnum P.I.\", Magnum often wore a ball cap for which sport's team?", "answer": "Detroit Tigers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d2", "question": "What movie was hyped \"Five Criminals, One Line Up, No Coincidence\"?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd4", "question": "In 1991, who erected three thousand blue and yellow umbrellas on the coasts of California and Japan?", "answer": "Christo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d5d", "question": "What classic movie, in which Charlton Heston is miscast as a Mexican cop, is sometimes called the last \"film noir\"?", "answer": "Touch of Evil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d2", "question": "How many claws does a domestic cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a2", "question": "Who was the youngest member of \"The Traveling Wilbury's\"?", "answer": "Tom Petty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339055", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, italy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be42", "question": "What sports team used the Swinging Friar as its team emblem until 1984?", "answer": "The San Diego Padres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded01fea2747c8aff16d23", "question": "In which sport is the America's Cup awarded?", "answer": "Sailboat racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21d", "question": "Which Commodore-produced computer came with 5 kB of static onboard memory?", "answer": "VIC-20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f5a", "question": "Which song by The Who did CSI: Miami use in its opening credits?", "answer": "Won't Get Fooled Again", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7209a9e54d890926f6e9", "question": "What is the biggest desert in Australia?", "answer": "Great Victoria Desert -- Located in Western and South Australia, it is home to several nature reserves and a national park.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abef", "question": "What country borders Ukraine to the east?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3ca8c73aa70ea0b70aed", "question": "In what year did Washington, D.C become the capital of the U.S.?", "answer": "1800", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e31", "question": "Who is Miguel Ferrer's mother?", "answer": "Rosemary Clooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c004", "question": "What is philately the study of?", "answer": "Stamps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "593c4c76b8198b9a2b077969", "question": "In which movie did Kim Basinger play a Bond girl?", "answer": "Never Say Never Again", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957b", "question": "What does Charlie Brown set out to do in the made-for-TV special, A Charlie Brown Christmas?", "answer": "Find the true meaning of Christmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d4", "question": "What part of the eye is damaged by glaucoma?", "answer": "The optic nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339375", "question": "In the movie \"Cast Away\", how long was Chuck Nolan marooned on the island?", "answer": "4 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfc5c9dc5ec6cd98a831b", "question": "Who painted \"The Birth of Venus\"?", "answer": "Sandro Botticelli", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a7596c0f9723ab15cb5e", "question": "Which US college or university has the largest endowment?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cdf3bb53d1af658864ee", "question": "What ocean is Christmas Island located in?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0e", "question": "Whose print of a banana is the cover of the 1967 album \"The Velvet Underground and Nico\"?", "answer": "Andy Warhol's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956c", "question": "In the animated movie, Rudolph the Red Nosed Reindeer, what was the name of Rudolph's dogsled driving friend?", "answer": "Yukon Cornelius", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac17", "question": "Victoria is the capital of which country and archipelago located northeast of Madagascar?", "answer": "Seychelles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a6", "question": "What is the literal translation of the word Brandy?", "answer": "Burned wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a422", "question": "What is the capital of New Zealand?", "answer": "Wellington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978c", "question": "Who played Rachel Green on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Jennifer Aniston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895f", "question": "Who murders Nancy in \"Oliver Twist\"?", "answer": "Bill Sikes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73e44eec85e375820b273", "question": "Where was the first UN summit on the environment, air pollution and global warming held, in 1992?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e02", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Eris?", "answer": "Discordia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69aa020565ad31a57c755", "question": "What city was the last imperial capital of Vietnam under the Nguyen dynasty?", "answer": "Hue", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eff", "question": "What artist painted himself sketching on the far right edge of his painting \"The Gross Clinic\"?", "answer": "Thomas Eakins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b907", "question": "How many times is a trains whistle blasted if it is about to move forward?", "answer": "two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b998", "question": "In the standard Monopoly game, what place will you land on if you roll 9 when on Park Avenue?", "answer": "Oriental Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe766aceec85e375820b286", "question": "In which city will you find the Brandenburg Gate?", "answer": "Berlin, Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff667c952a821ff76ae8aff", "question": "Which governing body classified tomatoes as a vegetable in the United States?", "answer": "U.S. Supreme Court (In a case regarding a tariff on imported vegetables, entrepreneur John Nix argued tomatoes are a fruit.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339034", "question": "The story \"The Rose and The Ring\" was written by which 19th century novelist?", "answer": "William Thackeray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338964", "question": "Who is Asterix' best friend?", "answer": "Obelix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d470c8f8e329de4f877895", "question": "What war lasted from June 5 to June 10, 1967?", "answer": "Six-Day War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb12b65ff7d326b622a67", "question": "What chemical is denoted by Cm?", "answer": "Curium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa74f73838c5c8a417f37", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2a", "question": "Who opened her first school, Rome's Casa dei Bambini, in 1907?", "answer": "Maria Montessori", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0dcd9fcbed638185eaa0d", "question": "The annual \"Christmas Book Flood\" is part of what country\u2019s holiday tradition?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc4696ce05a3942286f32", "question": "Who was Boy George's love interest when his band Culture Club was active in the 1980s?", "answer": "Bandmate Jon Moss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab3f", "question": "Juba is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a016", "question": "What actor was the narrator in the 2006 movie \"Charlotte's Web\"?", "answer": "Sam Shepard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93b126bd93ce3a4e5f69f", "question": "What notable scientist may have been driven mad by exposure to mercury?", "answer": "Isaac Newton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f32", "question": "What is the infirmity of Jake Barnes, the protagonist of \"The Sun Also Rises\"?", "answer": "He's impotent from a war wound", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb58bd5dad637d903c8811", "question": "The Band-Aid supergroup was formed in 1984 to raise money for famine relief in what troubled African nation?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339864", "question": "In Disney's \"Pinocchio\", what animal does Pinocchio begin to turn into after he reaches Pleasure Island?", "answer": "Donkey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ecaeb8c790ded87bb38fd8f", "question": "Which major motion film marks Bob Saget's directorial debut?", "answer": "Dirty Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59decf99ea2747c8aff16d20", "question": "Myomancy is the practice of what?", "answer": "Reading omens from the behavior of rats or mice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339872", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", what does the bottle marked \"Drink Me\" do?", "answer": "Shrinks you", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bfb", "question": "Which character did Aubrey Hepburn play in the movie \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\"?", "answer": "Holly Golightly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ec7231757c9fcac0ce7197a", "question": "What horse broke a Triple Crown drought lasting over 30 years?", "answer": "American Pharoah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe937706bd93ce3a4e5f66d", "question": "Cynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dogs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "596761c52b59efe0e9417ea5", "question": "The 13 stripes on the US Flag represent what?", "answer": "The 13 original colonies", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e7", "question": "What US state has been led by Woodrow Wilson and Jim McGreevey?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339057", "question": "Who wrote the \"Aeneid\"?", "answer": "Virgil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a41c", "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Ceylon?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eb016f83302ff91e46498", "question": "Who is often referred to as the \"Fifth Beatle\"?", "answer": "Stu Sutcliffe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a8f", "question": "What does \"J.R.R.\" stand for in J.R.R. Tolkien's name?", "answer": "John Ronald Reuel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e5", "question": "How much storage space did the original Amazon Kindle device have?", "answer": "256 MB", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e6", "question": "In what city is Gonzaga University located?", "answer": "Spokane, Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d38", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Cable Hogue\"?", "answer": "Sam Peckinpah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90d01152800b05cac20f0c", "question": "In what city was Bruce Lee born in?", "answer": "San Francisco, California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4dc", "question": "What two alcoholic ingredients is the traditional Martini cocktail made of?", "answer": "Gin and vermouth", "category": "general"}]